Douglass, Price, and Moody Family Papers
Douglass, Price, and Moody Family Papers
circa 1771-1911
4 linear ft.
Considerable collection of account books and diaries (some of the latter have been transcribed on DVDs) pertaining to the Douglass, Price, and Moody families of Pulaski, New York, from the nineteenth and twentieth centuries.
4794783
Biographical History
The Douglass, Price, and Moody families were residents of Pulaski, New York in nineteenth and twentieth centuries.
The individuals represented in this collection include Anna Price Douglass (1815-1889) and her husband, Volney Douglass (1810-1866); their two sons, Isaac Price Douglass (1834-1899) and Rufus Grant Douglass (1841-1924); as well as Isaac's wife, Martha Jane Moody Douglass (1840-1911); and Harry Ogden Hoffman Moody (1802-1874) who was Martha's uncle and Rufus's father-in-law.
Anna Price Douglass was the granddaughter of Revolutionary War patriot John Weed (1764-1834). Volney Douglass worked in agriculture.
Isaac Price Douglass (sometimes referred to in the diaries as "Ike") and Martha Moody Douglass owned and worked a farm near Salmon River. Their daughter, Anna Belle Douglass Moody, lived in Brooklyn, New York with her husband, Harry Anson Moody, and daughter, Dorothy Douglass Moody Barclay.
Rufus Grant Douglass married Mary Ellen Moody (1844-1924) in Pulaski and they had two children, Volney G. and Rufus M. In 1879 they relocated to Bloomington, Nebraska, where he lived until his death.
Mary Ellen Moody's father, Harry Ogden Hoffman Moody was one of the earliest natives of Jefferson County, New York. He farmed at Stone Mills, Jefferson County, but moved the family to Pulaski in 1830, where he continued farming, was a member of the Royal Arch Masons, and helped to establish the Republican party in the area.
The above information was found in various sources including the Find a Grave pages for Anna Price Douglass, Volney Douglass, Isaac Price Doulgass, Martha Moody Douglass, Rufus Grant Douglass, and Harry Ogden Hoffman Moody. Transcribed obituaries were also consulted. Genealogical information on Harry Odgen Hoffman Moody can be found in Genealogical and Family History of the County of Jefferson, New York by R. A. Oakes. Genealogical information on Anna Price Douglass and her father found in this Half-Shire Historical Society article.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Douglass, Price, and Moody Family Papers consists of financial account books, personal diaries, and transcriptions pertaining to the Douglass, Price, and Moody families of Pulaski, New York, from the nineteenth and twentieth centuries.
The Financial series contains account books and receipt fragments.
The Personal series contains daybooks and diaries of the family members.
Transcriptions are CDs containing typed copies of some of the daybooks.
Arrangement of the Collection
Financial material is in no particular order. Personal material is arranged alphabetically by individual and chronologically within the folder, with unidentified material at the end of the series. Transcriptions are arranged alphabetically by the title on the item.
Subject and Genre Headings
New York State; Douglass, Anna Price (1815-1889); Douglass, Volney (1810-1866); Douglass, Isaac Price (1834-1899); Douglass, Martha Moody (1840-1911); Douglass, Rufus Grant (1841-1924); Moody, Harry Ogden Hoffman (1802-1874); Douglass family.; Price family.; Moody family.; Pulaski (N.Y.) -- History.; Account books.; Clippings (information artifacts); Diaries.; DVDs.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. H. Douglass Barclay, 2016.
Inventory
- Financial material
  - Account book, 1771-1828; first few pages seem to include a list of the persons included in transactions (Oversize 2)
  - Fragments, includes receipts and fragments of daybooks (Box 1)
- Personal material
  Many of the diaries list weather, chores, health conditions, payments, and travel. Some, especially those of Anna Price Douglass and Martha Moody Douglass, include clippings. Also found in some of the Anna Price Douglass diaries are poetry, songs, and a recipe for asthma relief.
  - Douglass, Anna Price, 1862-1881; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Douglass, Anna Price, 1882-1889; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Douglass, Isaac Price, 1852-1883; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Doulgass, Isaac Price, 1884-1893; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Douglass, Isaac Price, 1894-1898; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Douglass, Martha Moody, 1899-1904; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Douglass, Martha Moody, 1905-1911; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Douglass, Rufus Price, 1849-1854; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Douglass, Rufus Price, 1856-1858 (Box 6)
  - Douglass, Rufus Price, 1865-1868 (Oversize 1)
  - Douglass, Volney, 1840-1848; second folder includes some of Anna Price Doulgass 1868-1875; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Moody, Harry Ogden Hoffman, 1853-1866 (Oversize 2)
  - Unidentified, 1858-1875; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Unidentified, 1868-1872 (Oversize 1)
- Transcriptions
  Some of the titles incorrectly spell "Douglass" with one "s" and they have been transcribed verbatim here.
  - Anna Price Douglas Diary, 10 Jul 2011; Microsoft Word Document (.docx) files, created by Dee Dee Barclay; douglass_price_moody_002; DVD (Box 6)
  - HOH [Harry Ogden Hoffman] Moody Diary, 2 Jan 2014; Microsoft Word Document (.docx) files, created by Dee Dee Barclay; douglass_price_moody_007; DVD (Box 6)
  - Isaac Price Diaries, parts 1, 2, 3, 2 Aug 2010; Microsoft Word Document (.docx) files, created by Dee Dee Barclay; douglass_price_moody_001; DVD (Box 6)
  - Isaac Price Douglas Diary, 13 Aug 2012; Microsoft Word Document (.docx) files, created by Dee Dee Barclay; douglass_price_moody_004; DVD (Box 6)
  - Martha Moody Douglass Diary, 17 Jun 2013; Microsoft Word Document (.docx) files, created by Dee Dee Barclay; douglass_price_moody_005; DVD (Box 6)
  - Martha Moody Douglass Diary, 3 Sep 2013; duplication of item "douglass_price_moody_005," Microsoft Word Document (.docx) files, created by Dee Dee Barclay; douglass_price_moody_006; DVD (Box 6)
  - Volney Douglass Diary, 16 Feb 2012; Microsoft Word Document (.docx) files, created by Dee Dee Barclay; douglass_price_moody_003; DVD (Box 6)